Enchanted dancing in a magical world!
Barbie in the 12 Dancing Princesses is a animation,
family film directed by Greg Richardson.
King Randolph sends for his cousin, Duchess Rowena, to help turn his daughters,
Princess Genevieve and her eleven sisters, into royal material.
But the Duchess strips the sisters of their fun,
including their favorite pastime: dancing.
When all hope may be lost, the sisters discover a secret passageway to
a magical land where they can dance the night away.
Genevieve (voice), played by Kelly Sheridan.
Duchess Rowena (voice), played by Catherine O'Hara.
King Randolph (voice), played by Christopher Gaze.
Ashlyn / Twyla (voice), played by Nicole Oliver.
Blair (voice), played by Jennifer Copping.
Courtney (voice), played by Lalainia Lindbjerg.
Barbie in the 12 Dancing Princesses is a 2006 animated dance film.
It premiered on Nickelodeon on September 10, 2006, and it
was later released to DVD on September 19.
The film was directed by Greg Richardson and loosely based on the
German fairy tale "The Twelve Dancing Princesses".
It is the ninth entry in the Barbie film series and features the
voice of Kelly Sheridan as the Barbie protagonist.
This is the first Barbie film to be distributed by Universal Studios Home Entertainment in North America, to-which Universal's
international subsidiary already handled distribution to the previous films under a deal with Entertainment Rights.
Music for the film was composed by Arnie Roth.
"Shine", the end title song written by Roth, Amy Powers and Rob
Hudnut, was nominated for a 2007 Emmy Award.
The film explores themes of princess, dance,
sibling relationship, magic, ballet.
The tone is lighthearted.